Andrew J. Ford

561-789-1773 | ajoeford@gmail.com | github: andrewjford | blog: https://andrewjford.github.io/

-

Full stack web developer with a passion for excellence and self-improvement. With experience in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming and a background in accounting, I have a diverse skillset. My five years as a CPA have allowed me to gain extensive knowledge and understanding of business and finance. I bring strong skills in client communications and an eagerness to learn that can help web development teams reach new potentials.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

National Park Explorer - Github (front-end) | Github (back-end) | Demo

A map based web application that allows users to explore U.S. National Parks.

- + Constructed a React front-end that provides a fast and responsive interface
- + Implemented Redux to better manage the application state of the React front-end
- + Created a Ruby on Rails API that passes JSON data to the React front-end through REST endpoints
- + Leveraged the U.S. National Park Service Data API to provide up-to-date information
- + Built with the Leaflet open-source JavaScript map library allowing for a map focused web application

AuditRequest - Github | Demo

A web application to facilitate audit communications between auditors and clients.

- + Constructed a Ruby on Rails MVC pattern back end serving HTML and a JSON REST API
- + Used jQuery, JavaScript, and custom CSS to provide AJAX functionality and responsive UI
- + Integrated gems Devise and Pundit to manage authorization and authentication
- + Implemented Oauth to allow access through Facebook and Github accounts

Expense Tracker - Github | Demo

A light-weight web application to record and review personal expenses.

- + Built with the Ruby framework Sinatra resulting in a thin yet powerful application
- + Created custom CSS and JavaScript to allow a quick and clean UI
- + Implemented on both SQLite and PostgreSQL databases

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, ¡Query, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Sysco Seattle (through Accounting Principals), Kent, WA

Internal Auditor, November 2016 - February 2017

- + Performed the annual self-assessment audit for the location, coordinating with various departments to meet audit deadlines
- + Analyzed procedures in a number of areas including sales, merchandising, credit, profit management, operations, and payroll

Caler, Donten, Levine, Cohen, Porter & Veil, P.A., West Palm Beach, FL

Audit Supervisor, June 2011 - August 2016

- + Progressed from audit staff to audit senior to audit supervisor
- + Managed audit engagements and supervised staff for over three years
- + Worked with a variety of clients and industries including restaurant and hospitality, real estate, food distribution, sports management, governmental and non-profits

Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, FL

Graduate Assistant, August 2010 - May 2011

+ Taught two labs per semester of Principles of Accounting II

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Flatiron School - 2017

+ Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript online program

Florida Atlantic University - Boca Raton, FL - May 2011

+ Master of Accounting and Bachelor of Business Administration with Scholars Distinction, Summa Cum Laude

Certified Public Accountant (CPA) - Since 2012 - Current license #35676 (Washington State)